MARIO VIENS

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

■ marviens@gmail.com tendermario.github.io/ 604-845-6782 Vancouver, Canada

in /in/mario-viens-5820b13b 🗘 tendermario

SUMMARY

I am a web developer working with great companies to create better web experiences. I enjoy wearing as many hats as possible as a full stack developer that keeps an eye on dev ops, has a strength in back-end, but also experienced with React. As a student and a teacher, I love to share knowledge and better those around me.

I started out in pure mathematics and now enjoy working on ground-breaking technology and innovation with experience in virtual reality, analytics, and the non-profit sector.

Every challenge is an opportunity for becoming better and, as such, learning new languages and undertaking new tasks drives me as I integrate these skills to my toolkit as a developer. I enjoy rapid iteration with a focus on structure, collaboration, and uniform code practices.

EMPLOYMENT

Feb. 2019 to Current Lighthouse Labs

Project Evaluator Lead · Vancouver, BC

Review and audit the Project Evaluators for consistency in evaluating the students projects.

Aug. 2018 to Current Mentor, "Project Expert"

Evaluate web development student projects and gave feedback on their code, as the only Project

Evaluator that is also a mentor, given title Project Expert.

Oct. 2017 to Mar. 2019 Project Evaluator

Evaluated web development student projects and gave feedback on their code.

July 2017 to Apr. 2019 uForis VR

Web Developer · Vancouver, BC

Main web developer developing the web-side of a VR company including the company-side panorama image processing software, prototyping their 3D panorama web viewer. Reworked the front-end to use Material.UI design language, and TypeScript. Created documentation for the web

app codebase.

Set up the continuous deployment architecture with BitBucket, AWS and PM2.

Worked with React, Redux, Node.js, Koa, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, and Three.JS.

Mar. 2017 to June 2017 Watercooler Analytics

Web Developer · Vancouver, BC

3 month contract as a full-time web developer for an analytics software company for convention centres and destination market organizations. Revamped their main website during this time and iterated their custom software builds. Worked in React, React Datagrid, Mongodb, and Ruby on Rails.

Jan. 2017 to Mar. 2017 Vancouver Community Network

Full-Stack Web Developer · Vancouver, BC

3 month contract as a full-time sole web developer working on the Binners' Project, a project with multiple pilot programs working with residents of the downtown east-side. Created a simple

Node/Express app that would connect residents and companies with binners.

Feb. 2014 to Sept. 2016 Convergys

Technical Support Professional III · Chilliwack, BC

VR Technical Support, Project Management, Documentation and Training.

Apr. 2012 to July 2012 Thompson Rivers University

Mathematics Researcher · Kamloops, BC

A part of a research team working on the Graceful Tree Conjecture in Graph Theory.

Dec. 2009 to Sept. 2016 Mathematics and Sciences Tutor · Kamloops, Vancouver

High school sciences and University mathematics tutor.

MARIO VIENS

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

EDUCATION

2016 Lighthouse Labs

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

2012 Thompson Rivers University

Mathematics

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES JavaScript, PostgreSQL, MYSQL, HTML5, CSS3, MongoDB, Ruby, Python, Pug/Jade, TypeScript

LIBRARIES, FRAMEWORKS, AND SYSTEMS

Rails, Django, React, Redux, Express, Node.js, jQuery, APIs, Webpack, CI/CD, AWS, Heroku

CUSTOMER SUPPORT

Technical Support, Knowledge Base Creation, Project Management, Customer Support, Zendesk,

Order Management, Documentation and Training

EDUCATION Tutoring, Training, Documentation Creation, Mentoring, Project Evaluation

PROJECTS

Heavy Visualizer

Web-based 3D customizable music visualizer. Can upload or drag and drop a song into the window, or enable mic. Created as a 2-person team in two weeks.

Used Javascript, ThreeJS, jQuery, Web Audio API

Nanoleaf Lightpanel CLI

A little test project to program Nanoleaf Light Panels by hitting the hardware's API. Is a fork of a fork of an unofficial python wrapper of the official API.

ordr

Online customer food ordering and restaurant order manager as a part of a 3-person team within 5 days. Automated restaurant calling and automated customer texting for immediate updates.

Used JavaScript, Express, EJS, Node.js, Postgres database hosted on Heroku, incorporated Twilio API

Make Food

A passion project web app with Nima Boscarino where you end the amount of money you want to spend and it sends you food. Uses puppeteer.

ACTIVITIES

June 2017 to Current

Lighthouse Labs Alumni Food & Code · Coordinator

A meet up for people that want to get together and code. No talks. No non-coders that are trying to network.